<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Is That Really What The Data Says?</title>
    <link>https://seanken.github.io/public/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Is That Really What The Data Says?</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <managingEditor>seankenneths@gmail.com (Sean Simmons)</managingEditor>
    <webMaster>seankenneths@gmail.com (Sean Simmons)</webMaster>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 21:43:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seanken.github.io/public/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Single Cell Level QC</title>
      <link>https://seanken.github.io/public/posts/single-cell-level-qc/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Apr 2023 21:43:39 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seankenneths@gmail.com (Sean Simmons)</author>
      <guid>https://seanken.github.io/public/posts/single-cell-level-qc/</guid>
      <description>Cell Level QC One thing that bothered me when I started working with 10X data (roughly 2016, after having worked with Smart-seq2 single nuclei data) is that for many metrics (percent intronic reads, percent intergenic reads, etc), though it was easy to get sample level values, it was much less straightforward to get cell level metrics. Since then the situation has gotten better, with much work on using different metrics to help remove low quality cells.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About me</title>
      <link>https://seanken.github.io/public/page/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <author>seankenneths@gmail.com (Sean Simmons)</author>
      <guid>https://seanken.github.io/public/page/about/</guid>
      <description>My name is Sean Simmons and I am currently a Senior Computational Biologist over at the Broad Institute in Joshua Levin&amp;rsquo;s group in the Stanley Center. I&amp;rsquo;ve been working with single cell and single nucleus data since before it was cool&amp;ndash;way back in 2016, when a few hundred cells was a big deal! I&amp;rsquo;ve worked on a lot of projects at the corner of RNA-seq (usually single nuclei or single cell, but sometmes spatial or bulk as well) and neuroscience (with a particular focus on neuropsychiatric disorders).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
